<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trong-Thang Pham&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trong-Thang Pham&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>vi-VN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BLEU, ROUGE-L, METEOR, CIDEr. A brief talk</title>
      <link>/note/2021/08/18/bleu-rouge-l-meteor-cider.-a-brief-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2021/08/18/bleu-rouge-l-meteor-cider.-a-brief-talk/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Main timeline:
 July 2002: Kishore Papineni, Salim Roukos, Todd Ward, and Wei-Jing Zhu from IBM published BLEU at ACL. July 25 - 26, 2004: Chin-Yew Lin from Information Sciences Institute, University of Southern California published ROUGE at the Workshop on Text Summarization Branches Out (WAS 2004). 2005: Satanjeev Banerjee and Alon Lavie from Language Technologies Institute, Carnegie Mellon University published METEOR at ACL 2005. And they continue published papers on each variant (or improved version) at ACL 2007, ACL 2008, Springer article 2010, NAACL/HLT 2010, ACL 2010, EMNLP 2011, and EACL 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implicit notation in Kullback-Leibler divergence</title>
      <link>/note/2021/08/18/implicit-notation-in-kullback-leibler-divergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2021/08/18/implicit-notation-in-kullback-leibler-divergence/</guid>
      <description>What do we know about KL div, the definition?
$$D_{\mathrm{KL}}(P \| Q)=\sum_{x \in \mathcal{X}} P(x) \log \left(\frac{P(x)}{Q(x)}\right)$$
The behaviour?
Fitting a unimodal approximating distribution q (red) to a multimodal $p$ (blue). Using KL(p || q) leads to a q that tries to cover both modes (a). However, using $\mathrm{KL}(\mathrm{q}|| \mathrm{p})$ forces $q$ to choose one of the two modes of $p(b, c)$.
Well, you see
I used to use this notation instead as definition: $$D_{\mathrm{KL}}(P - Q)=\sum_{x \in \mathcal{X}} P(x) \log P(x) - \log Q(x)$$ Because it is easier to rememeber, I mean there are two minus sign!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying Computer Science</title>
      <link>/2021/04/05/study-computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/05/study-computer-science/</guid>
      <description>Many study CS to find jobs, I study CompSci because:
 I want to know what fun about this field I want to write my own:  Android App Cross platform app Website Game Programming Language   I want to crack some program, hack some web. Legally of course. I want to participate in some competitions. I want to try to follow the trend of this field, like doing Machine Learning / Deep Learning, the bitcoin / blockchain things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Probabilistic Programming</title>
      <link>/2021/04/04/exploring-probabilistic-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/04/exploring-probabilistic-programming/</guid>
      <description>I asked a person who has higher experience than me to explore with me, just help me not being lonely.
The framework existed at that moment sucks, not stable, documents was lacking, hard to install or develop, pymc3 use Theano, pymc4 authors adviced to not use it, pyro was lacking documents.
I mainly looking into engineer stuff like how to use, what&amp;rsquo;s in the framework. And later I looked up to Causal Inference, where I try to write a document about a paper called CEVAE apply VAE to sold the Causal Inference problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hướng dẫn setup lại nếu lỡ cài lại OS (chẳng hạn Ubuntu)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/15/h%C6%B0%E1%BB%9Bng-d%E1%BA%ABn-setup-l%E1%BA%A1i-n%E1%BA%BFu-l%E1%BB%A1-c%C3%A0i-l%E1%BA%A1i-os-ch%E1%BA%B3ng-h%E1%BA%A1n-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/15/h%C6%B0%E1%BB%9Bng-d%E1%BA%ABn-setup-l%E1%BA%A1i-n%E1%BA%BFu-l%E1%BB%A1-c%C3%A0i-l%E1%BA%A1i-os-ch%E1%BA%B3ng-h%E1%BA%A1n-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Bên trong máy:
 Cài synaptic Cài chrome Cài gnome tweak Cài extension Hide Top Bar, Alt-Tab Switcher Popup Delay Removal, User Themes Cài dash to dock, nhưng chỉ vào chỉnh sao cho ẩn luôn cái dock luôn, rồi disable (vì nhìn xấu ._. , mình chỉ cần nó ẩn cái thanh kia thôi :D ) Cài theme mac mojave từ https://www.gnome-look.org/p/1275087/ và bộ icon https://www.pling.com/p/1305429/ cho dịu mắt, nhớ cài luôn shell theme là mc mojave nha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come back and change the way writing blog!</title>
      <link>/2019/07/22/come-back-and-change-the-way-writing-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/22/come-back-and-change-the-way-writing-blog/</guid>
      <description>Little changes, I have just deleted my old repo, move content folder to another repo, using blogdown this time, deploy on netlify.com
Well that&amp;rsquo;s all. The only reason I came back is my condition got worse. Hopefully it helps me &amp;lsquo;remember&amp;rsquo; like I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Week 1 Algs part 1 (Princeton)</title>
      <link>/note/2018/02/09/note-week-1-algs-part-1-princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2018/02/09/note-week-1-algs-part-1-princeton/</guid>
      <description>Phải mất khá lâu mình mới bắt đầu làm assignment của tuần này, do khá tự ti về khả năng bản thân rằng sẽ không làm nổi vì hầu như ai cũng nói khó, lần mò thì có người bảo phải cần hiểu trước programming rồi OOP các thứ, làm mình chật vật vì không biết bắt đầu từ đâu. Đến 2 hôm trước sau khi nộp xong deadline về turning point thì mới phải tự vả một cái là hình như mình lại vô vòng an toàn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Author My name is Trong-Thang Pham. I&amp;rsquo;m a student of University of Science, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.
About this blog I am having struggled with my forgetting knowledge easily. I don’t know why but a lot of times I forget what I have learned even it was only a week before. Currently, I’m using paper and pen for noting stuff. It’s good enough for the short term, but I lose my notes all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cài Ubuntu lần đầu</title>
      <link>/2018/01/24/c%C3%A0i-ubuntu-l-n-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/24/c%C3%A0i-ubuntu-l-n-u/</guid>
      <description>Cài Ubuntu lần đầu tiên Gian nan. Mà mọi lý do chủ yếu đến từ việc graphic card Nvidia :|
Nếu có máy có card rời, nếu ở màn hình menu chọn Try Ubuntu&amp;hellip; Install Ubuntu &amp;hellip; mà không chỉnh nomodeset thì sẽ bị kẹt ở logo screen có mấy cái chấm chấm phía dưới. Mình tốn mấy ngày để mò vì tưởng phải chỉnh trong BIOS, chỉnh sau khi có màn hình menu, &amp;hellip; Cuối cùng phát hiện, là tới menu bấm f6 và chọn nomodeset là xong &amp;lt;(&amp;quot;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
